[BRIGHT MUSIC]
INTERVIEWER: Welcome back
to, Are You Normalized?
[APPLAUSE]
Our final contestant
is Tina Tables
from Dataville University.
TINA TABLES: Hi, everyone.
I'd like to give a
shout out to my 3330
classmates and my favorite
professor, Dr. Kelly.
[APPLAUSE]
INTERVIEWER: That's
very nice, but I
didn't approve that shout out.
So we'll deduct a couple of
points right off the bat.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
All right, let's get normalized.
All right, Tina, here's
your final table design.
This table consists
of three columns--
Course, Professor, and Textbook.
As you can see, Course and
Professor are both underlined.
Are you ready, Tina?
TINA TABLES: I'm ready, Freddy.
INTERVIEWER: Who's Freddy?
Is he a new player?
Didn't authorize that either.
Anyways, let's get started.
Tina, is this table in
first normal form or not?
TINA TABLES: Let's see.
I use the D-R-O-P, DROP acronym,
to determine first normal form.
The D stands for data
types are consistent,
R, no repeating groups, O, one
piece of information per cell,
and P, primary key
is established.
Hmm, in this case, I can only
determine that a primary key
has been established.
We have a composite primary
key with Course and Professor.
So yes, it's in
first normal form.
INTERVIEWER: You got it.
[BELL CHIMES]
[APPLAUSE]
Round two, is the table
in second normal form?
TINA TABLES: We have a
composite primary key.
So it's possible to have
a partial dependency
or second normal form violation.
However, in this
case, Course alone
doesn't determine the
textbook, and Professor alone
doesn't determine the textbook.
Yes.
It's in second normal form.
INTERVIEWER: Absolutely correct.
[BELL CHIMES]
[APPLAUSE]
Round 3, is the table
in third normal form?
TINA TABLES: Third
normal form requires
no transitive dependencies.
No non-key can determine
another non-key.
There is only one non-key.
The table is in
third normal form.
INTERVIEWER: Well, I've
determined that you are correct.
[BELL CHIMES]
[APPLAUSE]
TINA TABLES: Yippee.
I did it.
I win, right?
Where are the streamers?
Where's the grand prize?
INTERVIEWER: Calm down, Tina,
or we will call security.
All right.
[APPLAUSE]
There is one final question
for the grand prize.
This one's a hard one.
Is every determinant
a candidate key?
TINA TABLES: Of course.
Wait.
What?
INTERVIEWER: It's an important
concept to normalization.
Everyone should know this one.
Is every determinant
a candidate key?
TINA TABLES: Yes.
In this table, every
determinant is a candidate key.
INTERVIEWER: Oh,
I'm sorry, Tina.
In this table, every determinant
is not a candidate key.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
Look closely at the columns,
Textbook and Course.
TINA TABLES: Well,
based on the data,
Textbook does determine Course.
But I thought third normal
form was all there was.
INTERVIEWER: A common mistake.
Typically, third normal
form is sufficient.
However, on very rare occasions,
normalization problems persist.
This table violates Boyce-Codd
normal form, or BCNF for short.
That said, BCNF doesn't
occur very often,
and it wasn't included in the
original paper on normalization.
However, in our sample table,
we have a non-key attribute,
Textbook, that determines part
of the composite primary key
course.
That's what we call
a BCNF problem.
TINA TABLES: Oh, I see.
With Textbook
determining Course,
then not all determinants
are candidate keys,
even though the table is in the
first, second, and third normal
form.
Textbook determines
part of the primary key.
INTERVIEWER: Exactly.
That's BCNF for you.
Let's fix the BCNF problem.
[APPLAUSE]
First, we create a new
table with, Textbook,
as the primary key and, Course,
as the non-key attribute.
Then we remove the Course
column from the original table
and make Textbook the foreign
key link to the new table.
In the original table, we
make Professor and Textbook
composite primary keys.
Now, every determinant is a key.
BCNF clean.
TINA TABLES: Wait,
this is the fix?
That design looks terrible.
INTERVIEWER: The
design is in BCNF.
TINA TABLES: Even though
you're squeaky clean and BCNF,
this whole design would be
better with a surrogate key.
Sometimes the best key
isn't natural at all.
It's a surrogate.
One column, identity 1, 1.
Simple joins, no
messy composites.
And your functional
dependencies stay clear.
INTERVIEWER: Wow.
You are correct.
[APPLAUSE]
I guess normalization
gets you far,
but design is about clarity,
and sometimes the real winner
is a surrogate key.
TINA TABLES: So did I
win the grand prize?
INTERVIEWER: Absolutely.
The grand prize is knowledge.
[APPLAUSE]
Congratulations, Tina.